Stathis Moraitidis

Senior Software Engineer

London, UK, London, UK



I am a Senior/Lead Software Engineer with more than 10 years of experience and a backend and full stack focus. For the past few years I've worked mostly at startups so I am used to wearing many hats. I care deeply about building elegant and maintainable solutions, while keeping a great user and developer experience in mind.

SKILLS -

Backend	Frontend	Devops		
Python TypeScript	HTML JavaScript / TypeScript	Docker		
PostgreSQL MySQL Node	CSS React Redux Vue	AWS (EC2, ECS, SNS, Lambda etc)		
Bash		GCP (GAE, GCE, Cloud Tasks, etc)		
		Jenkins		

Other

Linux	Git	Unity	OpenGL

WORK EXPERIENCE (5) -

Senior Backend/DevOps Engineer at Balena

Jan 2021 - Current

Q London/Remote, (EU)

- Took ownership of the existing internal CI/CD infrastructure. I maintain and improve it while helping colleagues with any queries.
- Working on a team that builds a new CI/CD system to accommodate internal as well as customers' needs.

Senior Backend Engineer at Hopster

Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

Q London, (UK)

- Responsible for the automated monthly delivery of content to partners. This involved a combination of GAE, GCE, Cloud Tasks, etc.
- Owned all server-mobile APIs. I was the point of contact for existing implementations as well as all new development in the area.
- Implemented integrations around user login flows (e.g. Apple Sign In).
- Facilitated team processes, worked towards enhancing developer experience and tackling technical debt.

Lead Software Engineer at We Got Pop

Dec 2015 - Dec 2019

• London, (UK)

Implemented various features across the company's stack and products. Technologies mostly used were Python,
JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL and AWS.

- Overviewed larger-scale projects, keeping track of progress and feeding back to product team.
- Line-managed two colleagues.
- Helped more junior members of the team with their everyday queries.
- Conducted interviews for development and product teams.
- Helped in shaping and organising some of the team's processes.

Software Engineer at IT2 Treasury Solutions

Sep 2013 - Nov 2015

Q London, (UK)

- Implemented new functionality, enhancements and fixes, using C++, C, Microsoft SQL Server.
- Participated actively in meetings with product owners and managers during the planning process.
- Created a tool that unifies all developers' internal programs, making them easily accessible.
- Occasionally undertook team-leading responsibilities.

Software Engineer at Fidessa

Jan 2011 - Sep 2013

♀ Woking, (UK)

- Implemented a regression test framework for testing various products across the company. I was keeping track of new requests, resolving issues or assigning them to other team members.
- Ported a process (~8k lines) from Java to C++.
- Extended an existing web-based tool for testing market trading.

PROJECTS (1) -

Bit Pong

https://github.com/stathismor/bit-pong

A mobile and web game, built in JavaScript.

EDUCATION (2)

MSc Computer Science at University of Piraeus

2007 - 2010

Athens, (GR)

Grade: 9.4

BSc Economics at University of Athens

2001 - 2006

Athens, (GR)

Grade: 6.5

INTERESTS

Movies			Games		Music				
	cinema	series	festivals		video games	board games		gigs	festivals
					development				

Sports

basketball cycling table tennis